It is actually a reality today
اصبحت حقيقة اليوم
that you can download products from the Web --
انه بامكانك تحميل منتجات من الانترنت
product data, I should say, from the Web --
بيانات المنتج اذا صح القول, من الانترنت
perhaps tweak it and personalize it
او ربما تعديلها و تخصيصها
to your own preference or your own taste,
الى ما تفضل او على ذوقك ,
and have that information sent
ومن ثم ارسال تلك المعلومات
to a desktop machine
الى جهاز سطح المكتب
that will fabricate it for you on the spot.
والذي سيقوم بتصنيعها لك فوراً
We can actually build for you,
في الحقيقة يمكننا ان نصنع لك,
very rapidly,
و بسرعة,
a physical object.
جسم مادي.
And the reason we can do this
والسبب في ذلك
is through an emerging technology
هو من خلال التكنولوجيا الناشئة
called additive manufacturing,
التي تسمى التصنيع المضاف
or 3D printing.
أو الطابعة ثلاثية الابعاد
This is a 3D printer.
هذه طابعة ثلاثية الابعاد
They have been around
ظلت موجودة
for almost 30 years now,
لقرابة الثلاثين عام,
which is quite amazing to think of,
وهذا الامر يثير الدهشة بمجرد التفكير فيه
but they're only just starting
ولكنها مجرد بداية فقط
to filter into the public arena.
لتصفيتها في الساحة العامة.
And typically, you would take data,
في العادة, تأخذ البيانات
like the data of a pen here,
مثل بيانات هذا القلم,
which would be a geometric representation of that product in 3D,
والذي من شانه ان يكون تصوير هندسي لذلك المنتج في الابعاد الثلاثية,
and we would pass that data with material
ومن ثم نرسل هذه البيانات مع مواد
into a machine.
الى آلة
And a process that would happen in the machine
والعملية التي تحدث داخل الآلة
would mean layer by layer that product would be built.
سيعني ان المنتج يصنع طبقة تلو الاخرى
And we can take out the physical product,
ويمكننا اخراج المنتج المرئي,
and ready to use,
جاهزة للاستخدام،
or to, perhaps, assemble into something else.
او ربما يجمع ليصبح شيئ اخر
But if these machines have been around for almost 30 years,
ولكن اذا كانت هذه الآلة موجودة منذ 30 عاما تقريبا
why don't we know about them?
لماذا لا نعرف عنها شي؟
Because typically they've been too inefficient,
لانها في العادة لم تكن فعالة,
inaccessible,
ويصعب الوصول اليها
they've not been fast enough,
لم تكن سريعة بما فيه الكفاية
they've been quite expensive.
و كانت مكلفة جدا
But today,
ولكن اليوم,
it is becoming a reality
اصبحت حقيقة
that they are now becoming successful.
ولقد اصبحت ناجحة
Many barriers are breaking down.
و لقد تم اختراق العديد من الحواجز
That means that you guys
وهذا يعني انكم, انتم
will soon be able to access one of these machines,
قريبا ستتمكنوا من استخدام هذه الآلات
if not this minute.
ان لم يكن الان
And it will change and disrupt
وهذا سيغير و يشوش
the landscape of manufacturing,
مجرى التصنيع
and most certainly our lives, our businesses
وبالتاكيد حياتنا و أعمالنا
and the lives of our children.
و حياة اطفالنا
So how does it work?
كيف تعمل اذن؟
It typically reads CAD data,
في العادة هي تقرأ بيانات الـ CAD,
which is a product design data
وهي بيانات تصميم المنتجات
created on professional product design programs.
أنشأت في برامج محترفة لتصميم المنتجات
And here you can see an engineer --
وهنا ترى مهندس --
it could be an architect or it could be a professional product designer --
قد يكون مهندس معماري او مصمم منتجات محترف --
create a product in 3D.
يصنع منتج ثلاثي الابعاد
And this data gets sent to a machine
وترسل تلك البيانات الى الآلة
that slices the data
التي تقوم بقص البيانات
into two-dimensional representations of that product
الى تمثيل ثنائي الابعاد لهذا المنتج
all the way through --
الى ان يقتحمه
almost like slicing it like salami.
مثل تشريح السلامي تقريبا
And that data, layer by layer, gets passed through the machine,
وتلك البيانات يتم نقلها عبر الماكينة طبقة تلو الاخرى,
starting at the base of the product
بدءا بقاعدة المنتج
and depositing material, layer upon layer,
وترسيب المواد طبقة فوق طبقة,
infusing the new layer of materials to the old layer
وغرس المواد الجديدة مع القديمة
in an additive process.
في عملية اضافية
And this material that's deposited
وهذه المواد المرسوبة
either starts as a liquid form
اما بدأت كسائل
or a material powder form.
او مواد على شكل مسحوق
And the bonding process can happen
وعملية التسنيد قد تحدث
by either melting and depositing or depositing then melting.
اما عن طريق تذويبه ثم ارسابه او ارسابه ثم تذويبه
In this case, we can see a laser sintering machine developed by EOS.
في هذه الحالة نرى جهاز تلبيد الليزر الذي طور بواسطة EOS
It's actually using a laser
انه في الحقيقة يستخدم الليزر
to fuse the new layer of material to the old layer.
ليمزج المواد القديمة مع الجديدة
And over time --
ومع مرور الزمن
quite rapidly actually, in a number of hours --
وبسرعة في الحقيقة, خلال بضع ساعات
we can build a physical product,
يمكننا صنع منتج مادي
ready to take out of the machine and use.
جاهز لاخراجه من الماكينة و الاستخدام
And this is quite an extraordinary idea,
وهذه فكرة استثنائية جدا,
but it is reality today.
لكنها اصبحت حقيقة اليوم
So all these products that you can see on the screen
لذا كل هذه المواد التي ترونها في الشاشة
were made in the same way.
صنعت بنفس الطريقة
They were all 3D printed.
باستخدام طابعات ثلاثية الابعاد
And you can see,
وكما ترون
they're ranging from shoes,
بدءا من الاحذية
rings that were made out of stainless steal,
خواتم تم صنعها باستخدام الفولاذ الغير قابل للالتصاق
phone covers out of plastic,
واغطية الهواتف التي صنعت من البلاستيك
all the way through to spinal implants, for example,
و حتى زراعة العمود الفقري
that were created out of medical-grade titanium,
والتي تم صنعها من التيتانيوم الطبي
and engine parts.
واجزاء المحرك
But what you'll notice about all of these products
ولكن الشيئ الذي سنلاحظه في هذه المنتجات
is they're very, very intricate.
هو انها معقدة جدا, جدا
The design is quite extraordinary.
التصميم استثنائي جدا
Because we're taking this data in 3D form,
لاننا نأخذ هذه البيانات في شكل 3D
slicing it up before it gets past the machine,
و نقسمها قبل ان تعبر الآلة
we can actually create structures
في الواقع يمكننا صنع اجسام
that are more intricate
اكثر تعقيدا
than any other manufacturing technology --
من اي تكنولوجيا صناعات اخرى --
or, in fact, are impossible to build in any other way.
او في الحقيقة, يصعب صناعتها اكثر من اي طريقة اخرى
And you can create parts with moving components,
كما يمكنك صناعة اجزاء باستخدام العناصر المتحركة,
hinges, parts within parts.
مفاصل, اجزاء داخل اجزاء
So in some cases, we can abolish totally
حتى في بعض الحالات, يمكننا الغاء
the need for manual labor.
الحاجة الى العمل اليدوي
It sounds great.
يبدوا شيئ عظيم
It is great.
هو فعلا عظيم
We can have 3D printers today
بامكاننا ان نمتلك طابعات ثلاثية الابعاد اليوم
that build structures like these.
بامكانها صنع هيئات مثل هذه
This is almost three meters high.
هذا طوله يقارب الثلاثة امتار
And this was built
و تم صنعه
by depositing artificial sandstone layer upon layer
عن طريق ترسيب حجر رملي صناعي طبقة فوق طبقة
in layers of about five millimeters to 10 mm in thickness --
طبقات يصل سمكها الى 5-10 مليمتر
slowly growing this structure.
وتنمية هذه البُنية ببطئ
This was created by an architectural firm called Shiro.
هذا تم صنعه بواسطة شركة الهندسة المعمارية, شيرو
And you can actually walk into it.
في الحقيقة, يمكنك ان تمشي خلاله
And on the other end of the spectrum,
و من الطرف الاخر
this is a microstructure.
هذا المجهر
It's created depositing layers
تم صنعه عن طريق ترسيب طبقات
of about four microns.
حجمها 4 ميكرون
So really the resolution is quite incredible.
ولذا فان دقته عالية جدا في الحقيقة
The detail that you can get today
والتفاصيل التي تحصل عليها
is quite amazing.
مدهشة للغاية
So who's using it?
اذن من الذي يستخدمها؟
Typically, because we can create products very rapidly,
لانه يمكننا صنع المنتجات بسرعة, في العادة
it's been used by product designers,
يستخدمه مصممي المنتجات
or anyone who wanted to prototype a product
او كل من اراد صنع نموذج بدئي
and very quickly create or reiterate a design.
وبسرعة صنع او اعادة صنع تصميم ما
And actually what's quite amazing about this technology as well
حقيقة الشيئ الاخر المثير للدهشة في هذه التكنولوجيا
is that you can create bespoke products en masse.
هو ان باستطاعة صنع منتج مفصل و بشكل جماعي
There's very little economies of scale.
يندر وجود اقتصاد بهذا الحجم
So you can now create one-offs very easily.
الان يمكنك صنع شيئ مرة واحدة بكل سهولة
Architects, for example,
مثلا, المهندسين
they want to create prototypes of buildings.
يريدون صنع منتج بدئي للمباني
Again you can see,
مرة اخرى, كما ترى
this is a building of the Free University in Berlin
هذا مبنى الجامعة الحرة في برلين
and it was designed by Foster and Partners.
و قد صممها فوستر وشركاءه.
Again, not buildable in any other way.
مرة اخرى, لا يمكن اعادة بنائه باية طريقة
And very hard to even create this by hand.
ويصعب جدا صنعه حتى بالايد
Now this is an engine component.
الان هذه قطعة من المحرك
It was developed by a company called Within Technologies
تم تطويرها من قبل شركة تدعى Within التكنلوجية
and 3T RPD.
و شركة 3T RPD
It's very, very, very detailed
و هي مفصلة جدا, جدا, جدا
inside with the design.
في داخل التصميم
Now 3D printing
الان طباعة ثلاثية الابعاد
can break away barriers in design
بامكانها كسر حواجز التصميم
which challenge the constraints
التي تهدد محددات
of mass production.
الإنتاج الشامل
If we slice into this product which is actually sitting here,
اذا شَرحنا هذا المنتج الذي امامنا
you can see that it has a number of cooling channels pass through it,
ستروا ان هنالك العديد من القنوات التبريدية التي تمر من خلاله
which means it's a more efficient product.
مما يعني انه منتج أكثر كفاءةً
You can't create this with standard manufacturing techniques
تستطيع صنعه عن طريق قياسات تقنيات التصنيع
even if you tried to do it manually.
حتى وان اردت صنعه يدويا
It's more efficient
فهو اكثر كفاءةً
because we can now create all these cavities within the object
لأنه بامكاننا الآن إنشاء جميع هذه التجويفات داخل الجسم
that cool fluid.
هذا السائل البارد
And it's used by aerospace
وهو يستخدم في مركبات الفضاء
and automotive.
وقطاع السيارات
It's a lighter part
وهو جزء اخف وزنا
and it uses less material waste.
يستخدم مواد تخلّف نفايات اقل
So it's overall performance and efficiency
لذا اداءه الكلي و كفائته
just exceeds standard mass produced products.
يفوق الإنتاج الشامل القياسي للمنتجات
And then taking this idea
و اخذ هذه الفكرة بعد ذلك
of creating a very detailed structure,
و تصنيع جسم بدقة عاليه
we can apply it to honeycomb structures
يمكننا تطبيقة على اقراص العسل
and use them within implants.
و استخدامها داخل الغرسات
Typically an implant
في العادة, الغرسات
is more effective within the body
هي اكثر فعالية داخل الجسم
if it's more porous,
اذا سهل اخترقها
because our body tissue will grow into it.
لان انسجة الجسم ستنمو عليها
There's a lower chance of rejection.
و ستقل نسبة الرفض
But it's very hard to create that in standard ways.
و لكن صعب جدا صنعه بالطريقة العادية
With 3D printing,
باستخدام طابعة الـ 3D
we're seeing today
اليوم نحن نبحث
that we can create much better implants.
لصنع اعضاء غرس افضل
And in fact, because we can create
في الحقيقة, لانه يمكننا صناعة
bespoke products en masse, one-offs,
منتجات مفصلة كثيرة في مرة واحدة
we can create implants
يمكننا صنع الاعضاء
that are specific to individuals.
تختص بالافراد
So as you can see,
كما ترى
this technology and the quality of what comes out of the machines is fantastic.
التكنلوجيا و الدقة التي تصنعها هذه الماكينة شيئ عظيم
And we're starting to see it being used
نحن نبدأ الان نرى انها يتم استخدامها
for final end products.
لمنتجات نهائية
And in fact, as the detail is improving,
و حقيقة, بما ان التفاصيل في تحسن
the quality is improving,
والجودة في تحسن
the price of the machines are falling
اسعار الماكينات ايضا انخفضت
and they're becoming quicker.
و هي الان اكثر سرعة
They're also now small enough
كما انها الان صغيرة لدرجة
to sit on a desktop.
انه يمكنك وضعها على المكتب
You can buy a machine today for about $300
تستطيع اليوم شراء ماكينة بسعر $300
that you can create yourself,
يمكنك تصنيعها بنفسك
which is quite incredible.
و هذا شيئ لايصدق
But then it begs the question,
و هذا يطرح السؤال
why don't we all have one in our home?
لماذا لا يكون لدينا جميعا واحدة في بيوتنا؟
Because, simply, most of us here today
لانه, ببساطة, معظمنا هنا اليوم
don't know how to create the data
لا يعلم كيف يصنع بيانات
that a 3D printer reads.
بامكان طابعات الـ 3D قراءتها
If I gave you a 3D printer,
اذا اعطيتك طابعة 3D
you wouldn't know how to direct it
لن تعلم كيف يمكنك تشغيلها
to make what you want it to.
لتجعلها تعمل ما تريده منها
But there are more and more
ولكن هناك المزيد من
technologies, software and processes today
التقنيات والبرمجيات والعمليات اليوم
that are breaking down those barriers.
التي تكسر تلك الحواجز اليوم
I believe we're at a tipping point
أعتقد أننا الان نقف في نقطة تحول
where this is now something
حيث ان هذا الان شيئ
that we can't avoid.
لا نستطيع تجنبه
This technology
هذه التكنلوجيا
is really going to disrupt
في الواقع ستعرقل
the landscape of manufacturing
مجرى الصناعات
and, I believe, cause a revolution
وأعتقد، انها ستسبب ثورة
in manufacturing.
في الصناعات
So today,
لذا اليوم
you can download products from the Web --
يمكنك تحميل المنتجات من الويب
anything you would have on your desktop,
اي شيئ تجده على سطح مكتبك
like pens, whistles, lemon squeezers.
مثل الأقلام، والصافرات، وعصارات الليمون.
You can use software like Google SketchUp
يمكنك استخدام البرامج مثل جوجل إسكتش أب
to create products from scratch
لصنع منتجات من البداية
very easily.
بكل سهولة
3D printing can be also used
ويمكن أيضا استخدام طباعة الـ 3D
to download spare parts from the Web.
لتحميل قطع الغيار من الويب
So imagine you have, say,
تخيل ان لديك,
a Hoover in your home
هوفر في منزلك
and it has broken down. You need a spare part,
و قد كسرت. انت تحتاج الى قطعة غيار
but you realize that Hoover's been discontinued.
ولكن اكتشفت ان الهوفر اوقف انتاجها
Can you imagine going online --
هل تستطيع تخيل دخول الويب --
this is a reality --
هذه حقيقة
and finding that spare part
و ايجاد قطعة الغيار
from a database of geometries
من قاعدة بيانات هندسية
of that discontinued product
من المنتج الموقوف
and downloading that information, that data,
و تحميل تلك المعلومات, تلك البيانات
and having the product made for you at home,
وتصنيع ذلك المنتج في منزلك
ready to use, on your demand?
جاهز للاستخدام, تحت طلبك؟
And in fact, because we can create spare parts
و في الحقيقة لانه بامكاننا صنع قطع الغيار
with things the machines
باستخدام اشياء الماكينات
are quite literally making themselves.
بكل معنى الكلمه تصنعها بنفسها
You're having machines fabricate themselves.
تجد ان الماكينات تصنع نفسها
These are parts of a RepRap machine,
هذه اجزاء من آلة الريب راب
which is a kind of desktop printer.
و هي نوع من انواع طابعات سطح المكتب
But what interests my company the most
ولكن الشيئ الذي يهم شركتي اكثر
is the fact that you can create
هو حقيقة ان بامكانك صنع
individual unique products en masse.
منتجات فريدة من نوعها بكميات ضخمة
There's no need to do a run
لاحاجة لتصنيع
of thousands of millions
الاف المليونات
or send that product to be injection molded in China.
أو إرسال ذلك المنتج ليذوب ويتم صبه في الصين
You can just make it physically on the spot.
يمكنك صنعه حقيقة في الحال
Which means
مما يعني
that we can now present to the public
ان بامكاننا الان ان نقدم للمجتمع
the next generation of customization.
الجيل الجديد من التخصيص
This is something that is now possible today,
وهذا شيئ ممكن اليوم
that you can direct personally
يمكنك توجيهه شخصيا
how you want your products to look.
كيف تريد ان يبدو منتجك
We're all familiar with the idea
كلنا معتادون على هذه الفكرة
of customization or personalization.
فكرة التشخيص
Brands like Nike are doing it.
ماركات مثل نايكي تقوم بذلك
It's all over the Web.
في كل مكان على الويب
In fact, every major household name
في الواقع, الشركات المنزلية الرئيسية
is allowing you
تسمح لك
to interact with their products
بالتفاعل مع منتجاتها
on a daily basis --
بشكل يومي --
all the way from Smart Cars
من السيارات الذكية
to Prada
مرورا بمنتجات برادا
to Ray Ban, for example.
و راي بان, مثلا
But this is not really mass customization;
و لكن ليس هذا تخصيص كبير
it's known as variant production,
هذا يعرف بالانتاج المختلف
variations of the same product.
اختلاف في نفس المنتج
What you could do is really influence your product now
الذي يمكنك فعله الان هو التأثير في منتجك
and shape-manipulate your product.
و التلاعب في شكل المنتج
I'm not sure about you guys,
لا اعرف عنكم
but I've had experiences
ولكنني حدث و ان جربت
when I've walked into a store and I've know exactly what I've wanted
عندما دخلت الى المتجر وانا اعرف بالضبط ما اريده
and I've searched everywhere for that perfect lamp
ولقد فتشت في كل مكان لذلك المصباح المثالي
that I know where I want to sit in my house
وانا اعرف اين اريد و ضعه في بيتي
and I just can't find the right thing,
ولكني لا استطيع ايجاد الشيئ الصحيح
or that perfect piece of jewelry
او تلك القطعة المثالية من المجوهرات
as a gift or for myself.
لاهديها, او لنفسي
Imagine that you can now
تخيل أنك تستطيع الآن
engage with a brand
التعامل مع ماركة
and interact,
والتفاعل،
so that you can pass your personal attributes
بحيث يمكنك تمرير صفاتك الشخصية
to the products that you're about to buy.
على المنتجات التي أنت على وشك شراءها
You can today
تستطيع اليوم
download a product with software like this,
تحميل منتج مع برامج مثل هذا،
view the product in 3D.
عرض المنتج في 3D.
This is the sort of 3D data
هذا هو النوع من بيانات الـ 3D
that a machine will read.
التي يمكن للآله قراءتها
This is a lamp.
هذا مصباح
And you can start iterating the design.
ويمكنك البدأ بتكرار التصميم.
You can direct what color that product will be,
يمكنك توجيه لون المنتج ماذا سيكون،
perhaps what material.
او ربما, المواد
And also, you can engage in shape manipulation of that product,
و ايضا يمكنك الاشتراك في التلاعب بشكل المنتج
but within boundaries that are safe.
ولكن ضمن حدود آمنة.
Because obviously the public are not professional product designers.
لانه بكل وضوح, العامة ليسوا بمصممين محترفين
The piece of software will keep an individual
فإن قطعة من البرمجيات بامكانها إبقاء الفرد
within the bounds of the possible.
في حدود المعقول
And when somebody is ready to purchase the product
و عندما يكون شخص ما على استعداد لشراء المنتج
in their personalized design,
في تصميمه الشخصي
they click "Enter" and this data gets converted
فانه يضغط "دخول" و تلك البيانات تتحول
into the data that a 3D printer reads
الى بيانات تستطيع الطابعة قراءتها
and gets passed to a 3D printer,
و يتم نقلها الى الطابعة
perhaps on someone's desktop.
ربما, على سطح مكتب احدهم
But I don't think that that's immediate.
لكنني لا اظن ان هذا سيحدث على الفور
I don't think that will happen soon.
ولا اعتقد انه سيحدث قريبا
What's more likely, and we're seeing it today,
الشيئ الارجح, و الذي نراه اليوم,
is that data gets sent
ان تلك البيانات يتم ارسالها
to a local manufacturing center.
الى مركز التصنيع المحلي
This means lower carbon footprint.
وهذا يعني خفض الأثر الكربوني
We're now, instead of shipping a product across the world,
نحن الآن، بدلا من شحن المنتجات في جميع أنحاء العالم،
we're sending data across the Internet.
نرسل بيانات عبر الانترنت
Here's the product being built.
هذا منتج تم بناءه
You can see, this came out of the machine in one piece
كما ترى, يتم اخراجه من الآله في قطعة واحدة
and the electronics were inserted later.
وادراج الالكترونيات في وقت لاحق
It's this lamp, as you can see here.
فمن هذا المصباح، وكما ترون هنا
So as long as you have the data,
ما دام لديك بيانات
you can create the part on demand.
تستطيع صنع الجزء عند الحاجة
And you don't necessarily need to use this
وأنت لا تحتاج بالضرورة لاستخدامه
for just aesthetic customization,
فقط للتشخيص التجميلي
you can use it for functional customization,
يمكنك استخدامه للتشخيص الوظيفي
scanning parts of the body
فحص أجزاء من الجسم
and creating things that are made to fit.
وصنع الأشياء التي صنعت لتتناسب
So we can run this through to something like prosthetics,
يمكننا اجراء هذا على اشياء مثل الجراحات الترقيعية،
which is highly specialized to an individual's handicap.
ولقد قصصت و بشدة للافراد ذوي الاعاقة
Or we can create very specific prosthetics
او نستطيع صنع جراحات ترقيعية خاصة للغاية
for that individual.
لذلك الشخص
Scanning teeth today,
فحص الاسنان اليوم
you can have your teeth scanned
تستطيع فحص اسنانك
and dental coatings made in this way to fit you.
و طلاء اسنان صنع بهذه الطريقة ليناسبك
While you wait at the dentist,
أثناء انتظارك عند طبيب الأسنان،
a machine will quietly be creating this for you
الآلة تقوم بكل هدوء بطلاءه لك
ready to insert in the teeth.
جاهز لادراجه الى اسنانك
And the idea of now creating implants,
والفكرة الان هي زراعة الاعضاء
scanning data, an MRI scan of somebody
البيانات الفحص ، والتصوير بالرنين المغناطيسي من شخص ما
can now be converted into 3D data
يمكن الآن تحويلها إلى بيانات 3D
and we can create very specific implants for them.
و يمكنا الان تصميم زراعة مخصصة جدا لهم
And applying this
وتطبيق هذا
to the idea of building up what's in our bodies.
على فكرة بناء ما هو داخل أجسامنا
You know, this is pair of lungs and the bronchial tree.
تعلمون ان هذه رئتان و قصبتين هوائيتين
It's very intricate.
انها معقدة للغاية
You couldn't really create this or simulate it in any other way.
لن تتمكن من صنع هذا أو محاكاته باي وسيلة أخرى
But with MRI data,
ولكن باستخدام بيانات التصوير بالرنين المغناطيسي،
we can just build the product,
بامكاننا فقط ان نبني المنتج
as you can see, very intricately.
كما ترون بكل تعقيد
Using this process,
باستخدام هذه العملية
pioneers in the industry are layering up cells today.
الرواد في الصناعة يقومون الان بتصفيف الخلايا اليوم
So one of the pioneers, for example, is Dr. Anthony Atala,
واحد من الرواد، على سبيل المثال، هو الدكتور أنتوني أتالا,
and he has been working
عمل على
on layering cells to create body parts --
تصفيف الخلايا لصنع اعضاء الجسم --
bladders, valves, kidneys.
المثانات، والصمامات، والكليتين
Now this is not something that's ready for the public,
هذا ليس شيئا جاهزا للعامة حاليا,
but it is in working progress.
ولكنه عمل في تقدم
So just to finalize, we're all individual.
و للختام, كلنا كأشخاص
We all have different preferences, different needs.
كلنا لدينا تفضيلات مختلفة و احتياجات مختلفة
We like different things.
نحب أشياء مختلفة
We're all different sizes and our companies the same.
كلنا احجامنا و شركاتنا مختلفة
Businesses want different things.
الشركات يريدون أشياء مختلفة
Without a doubt in my mind,
بدون ادنى شك
I believe that this technology
أعتقد أن هذه التكنولوجيا
is going to cause a manufacturing revolution
ستتسبب في ثورة صناعات
and will change the landscape of manufacturing as we know it.
و ستغير مجرى الصناعات على غير المعتاد
Thank you.
شكرا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)